曾奶奶  快一点
Maw Maw! Hurry up!
露天电影要开始啦
It's time for the yard movie.
那小玩意是谁
Who's the pygmy?
它怎么占了我的位
What's it doing in my seat?
曾奶奶  这是你的重孙女喜旺呀
Maw Maw, this is your great-granddaughter, Hope.
你他妈又是谁啊
Who the heck are you?
好吧  我觉得曾奶奶又糊涂了
Yeah, I think Maw Maw's confused again.
曾奶奶  你最后记得的事情是什么
Maw Maw, what's the last thing you remember?
那个熊孩子出去买泡泡糖味的冰激凌
That dopey looking kid went out to get bubblegum ice cream.
哇  她把过去三年的事都忘干净了
Wow. She's forgotten, like, the last three years.
乐器走起
Get out the instruments,
她需要记忆重启
she needs a memory reset.
一  二  三
One, two, three...
吉米带了个连环杀手回家*
*Jimmy brought home a serial killer
他一时色急上了她*
*And he nailed her before he knew
警察把她关进牢房  但在她的肚子里*
*They locked her up without a key, but in her guilty belly
一个婴儿正在长大*
*a darling baby grew
吉米是个苦逼的单身爸爸*
*Jimmy was a struggling single father
直到他遇到那个贤惠的女娃*
*Till he found a girl to help him cope
那是你的曾孙吉米*
*That's your great-grandson Jimmy
和他的妻子塞布丽娜*
*And his wife Sabrina
以及他们的女儿*
*And...their daughter...
猴子
Monkey?
或许一些特殊事件能触发她的记忆
Maybe some specifics would jog her memory.
曾奶奶  你可还记得
Maw Maw, remember how...
喜旺被卡在了维吉妮亚的杂物房*
*Hope got stuck in Virginia's shed
你的高超拆物术拯救了她  毫发无伤*
*You Jenga-ed her out or she'd be dead
我们和维吉妮亚的表姐去了维加斯*
*We went to Vegas with Virginia's cousin
伯特一开始是犹太人  结果发现他并不是*
*Burt was Jewish and then he wasn't
我们把发明卖给了安德鲁・戴斯・克雷*
*Pitched our inventions to Andrew Dice Clay
吉米弗兰克结了婚  身非基佬心好累*
*Jimmy married Frank, although he's not gay
我们和吉米的养父母见了面*
*We met Jimmy's almost family,
那帮种族歧视分子把我们嫌*
*a bunch of racists
还逮住一只松鼠强奸犯  真讨厌*
*We caught a squirrel who was a rapist
我们把你从养老院偷出来*
*We busted you out of a nursing home
他们和熊大战  我们却与之跳舞*
*They fought a bear, we danced with some
买了一台二手时光机器*
*Bought a used time machine
-来了一场糖果大战  -训练了一头猪*
*- Fought a giant candy war - Trained a pig
忍痛卖了猪猪侠*
*Sold pigurines
还有太多太多回忆*
*And so, so, so much more...
曾奶奶  你现在想起来了吗
Maw Maw, do you remember it now?
你还是觉得稀里糊涂的吗
Are you still confused?
我记得
Nope. That's...
巴尼  弗兰克  怪怪的那个是雪莉*
*Barney, Frank, the odd one's Shelley
舞王丹*
*Dancin' Dan
我知道我是曾奶奶*
*I know I'm Maw Maw
我孙女维吉妮亚*
*My granddaughter, Virginia
她老公伯特*
*Her husband Burt,
我的曾孙吉米*
*my great-grandson Jimmy
他妻子塞布丽娜*
*His wife Sabrina
以及他们的女儿*
*And... their daughter...
我记得是叫
I want to say...
埃德加
Edgar.
喜旺
Hope!
我希望你的名字也叫埃德加
I hope your name is Edgar, too--
那就好笑死了
that would be hilarious.
伯特
Burt!
快跟我来  我又看到他了
You got to come with me. I saw him again.
那个白人版的摩根・弗里曼[著名演员]吗
That guy who looks like white Morgan Freeman?
不  是"闪现男"
No. deja vu Man!
该死  我老是遇不着他
Damn, I always miss him.
-他们在说谁呢  -闪现男
- What are they talking about? - deja vu Man.
他是我老妈意淫出来的朋友
He's mom's imaginary friend.
才不是  他是真实存在的
He's not imaginary. He's real.
每隔几年就会闪现一次
He shows up every few years.
还记得第一次见面
The first time,
我正在等曾爷爷来接我放学
I was waiting for Paw Paw to pick me up from school.
还当他是个变态呢
I just thought he was a pervert,
但后来发现他胡子剃得超干净
but then when I saw he didn't have a mustache,
我琢磨着自己是不是
I assumed I was being discovered
被便衣模特星探发现了
by an undercover modeling talent scout.
门儿敲敲敲  清洁工来到
他总是在我最不上照的时候出现
He always shows up when I'm at my least photogenic.
最近一次是在大约一年前
The last time before today was about a year ago.
我们必须速度赶过去
We got to get there quick.
我跟踪他到了理发店
I followed him to the barbershop
他的头发可不多  分分钟就剪完了
and he doesn't have a lot of hair.
轮到谁转了啊
Someone gonna spin, or what?
他在那儿
There he is.
让我看看
Let me see.
看见了吗
You see him?
没  被洗剪吹合唱团挡住了
No. The Hair-monizers are in the way.
他们看上去唱得很欢乐
They look like they sound great.
快看  饼干男也在
Hey! Cookie Man is in there, too!
哪个
Which one?
窗户旁边正刮胡子的那个
The guy by the window getting a shave.
但那个就是闪现男啊
But... the guy by the window getting a shave, that's deja vu Man!
所以说闪现男就是饼干男
Then deja vu Man is also Cookie Man!
好吧  我忍不住了
Okay, fine, I'll bite--
-谁是饼干男  -我爹意淫出来的朋友
- who's Cookie Man? - Dad's imaginary friend.
饼干男好多年前就出现了
Cookie Man started coming around years ago
当时吉米还是个小孩
when Jimmy was little.
他总是出现在公园
He would show up at the park
分饼干给我们吃
and share his cookies with us.
还老打听吉米的事
He was always asking about Jimmy.
这娃可聪明了
He's a very smart baby.
我觉得他是遗传到我的优良基因
I think he gets from me.
-你是在喝母乳吗  -是啊  你想来点吗
- Are you drinking breast milk? - Yeah. You want some?
不  我就免了吧
Uh, no, I'm gonna pass.
那个面具可真有意思
Well, that's an interesting mask.
他扮的是谁啊
Uh, what's he supposed to be?
我们问过他万圣节想装扮成谁
We asked him what he wanted to dress up as for Halloween--
他说  吉米
he said, "Jimmy."
他只会说这个词
It's the only word he knows.
-对吧  儿子  -吉米
- Isn't that right, boy? - Jimmy.
你想再来点饼干吗
Want some more cookies?
吉米
Jimmy.
你几岁了
How old are you?
吉米
Jimmy.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
饼干
Cookie!
太好了  他学了个新词
Hey! He learned a new word!
我就跟你说他很聪明吧
Told you he was smart.
他上个月还刚出现过
He even showed up last month
当时我正带喜旺在公园玩
when I was in the park with Hope.
其实有很多陌生人
You know, there's a lot of strangers
在镇上散发零食给孩子们吃
who hand treats to kids in this town,
但目前为止  你的饼干是最美味的
but your cookies are by far the best.
伯特  我可不是陌生人
Burt, please, I'm not a stranger.
我是饼干男
I'm Cookie Man.
我真的很抱歉  伯特
I'm really sorry, Burt.
我还以为饼干男是你瞎编出来的呢
I always thought you made up Cookie Man
帮着吉米不好好吃晚饭找借口
just to cover for spoiling Jimmy's dinner.
我也很抱歉  我也常怀疑闪现男
I'm sorry, too. I sometimes wondered if deja vu Man
是你那疯狂阴谋论的又一产物
was just another one of your crazy conspiracy theories,
就像飞碟啦  大脚怪啦
like UFOs or Bigfoot
或什么特拉华州根本不存在
or that Delaware doesn't actually exist.
有本事说出一个去过特拉华州的人试试看
Name one person that's ever been to Delaware.
那个在刮胡子的男人
Did you say that deja vu-slash-Cookie Man
就是你们说的闪现饼干男
was the one in front getting a shave?
-是啊  怎么了  -好奇先生也是他
- Yeah. Why? - 'Cause that's also Super Curious Guy!
好奇先生是谁啊
Who's Super Curious Guy?
那是吉米意淫出来的朋友
That would be Jimmy's imaginary friend.
他是真实存在的
He is not imaginary.
这人总是时不时会在码头出现
He's this guy who shows up every now and then on the loading dock
跟我问七问八
and asks me tons of questions.
我记得有一次他说
I remember once that he said...
吉米  没空听你扯
Jimmy! There's no time!
知道你有好些趣事可以说
I'm sure you got two or three funny memories you could describe,
但我们现在得先想出下一步对策
but we need to figure out what to do next.
是白人版摩根・弗里曼
Ooh! White Morgan Freeman!
哦天哪
Oh, my God.
闪现男  饼干男  好奇先生居然
Deja Vu Man, Cookie Man, and Super Curious Guy is also
还是个外科医生  96年我见他偷了我妈的肾
Roofie Surgeon, who I saw steal my mother's kidney in 1996.
此话当真
Really?
姐扯的  姐那时太寂寞
No, I just felt left out.
伯特  我们怎么打算
Okay, Burt, how should we play this?
你们干啥不直接过去
You guys, why don't you just go over there
问他到底打的什么主意
and ask him what's going on?
你提得出这种建议
You make suggestions like that,
还不知道自己当年为啥寂寞
you wonder why you get left out?
多谢提议  塞布丽娜
Thanks, Sabrina.
我们都知道  他是公务员
For all we know, he works for the government
人一个不高兴就能把咱扔杰罗尼莫湾关上一辈子
and can lock us all up in Geronimo Bay for the rest of our lives.
罗杰尼莫湾  二次元高级军事基地
他要走了  咱得跟上
Oh, he's leaving, we've got to follow him,
看看他背后的主子到底是谁
find out who he works for.
高  实在是高
Good idea. Good idea.
吉米  记得我们讨论过
Jimmy, do you remember
当你爹妈发神经时
how we talked about not letting your parents
我们不能总被卷进去吗
drag us into something crazy every week?
我得去接喜旺了
Guys, I got to go pick up Hope.
我这不是在努力做一个负责的爹嘛
I am trying to be a responsible parent.
糟了  他要蹬上自行车了
Oh, crap, he's getting on his bike.
我们是把卡车开来  还是徒步跟踪
Should we get the truck, or follow him on foot?
都不用
Neither.
我跟着呢
I got him.
我不知道这人的真实身份  但他绝对是个土豪
I don't know who this guy is, but he must be loaded.
三季汽车旅馆
他住的可是三季汽车旅馆
He's staying at the Three Seasons Motel.
他到底在搞什么
What is he doing in there?
自己出谜自己猜
He's either doing solo charades
或者打太极
or Tai Chi.
如果谜面就是太极的话  那他就是边猜边打
Or both, if the clue is "Tai Chi."
咱必须得承认  这人还有点意思
I got to be honest, he sounds like an interesting guy.
我觉得他肯定是公务员
I'll bet he works for the government.
我不明白
I just don't understand
他干啥对我们的生活那么感兴趣
why they care so much about what we're doing.
反正哥无聊的时候
Well, when I'm bored, I like to look up
就爱上网看看怎么造炸弹
how to build bombs on the Internet.
九十年代  姐无聊时还爱去放点小火呢
And I was a bit of a firebug in the '90s.
也许他跟踪我们也是有苦衷的
Maybe he's following us for a good reason.
说不定他是黑客帝国里的人
Maybe he's one of those guys from The Matrix.
那样他就能跟我说说黑客帝国到底是咋回事了
Then he could explain The Matrix to me.
他要走了
Oh, he's leaving.
机会来了
All right, here's our chance--
我们溜进他房间  去查明此人真实身份
we're gonna break into his room and find out who he is.
听着挺像回事儿
Sounds like a plan.
哥只要一个打火机
All I'm gonna need is a lighter,
一瓶洁厕剂
a bottle of toilet bowl cleaner,
还有一老式闹钟
and an old-fashioned alarm clock.
就能在他门上炸个洞出来
We'll blow a hole right through his door.
或者我们可以直接用"请勿打扰"牌直接撬开门
Or we could just jimmy it open with the "Do Not Disturb" Sign.
真豪华
Whoa! Fancy.
摇滚明星就得在这种房间里嗑药啊
This is the type of room a rock star would O.D. In.
来试试这个
Hey, check this out.
咋了
What? What is it?
全宇宙最销魂的床
The greatest bed ever made.
你必须来试试
You got to try this.
伯特  别这样  我们得
Burt, we can't. We got to...
我的神哪
Oh, my God.
这床硬度恰好  柔软适度
It's both firm and soft.
姐好像都看到天堂了
It's like lying on Santa Claus.
搞什么飞机
What the hell?
姐的整个人生啊
It's, like, my whole life.
这太诡异了
This is creepy.
在他回来
Let's get out of here quick,
把我们的脸剥了做面具前  我们快溜
before he comes back and makes masks out of our faces.
现在我也有他的照片了
Now I got a picture of him.
哇  这张把我俩都照得不错嘛
Wow. We both looked really good in that shot.
那倒是
You're right.
如果他不是变态杀人狂的话
If he doesn't turn to be a weirdo pervert killer,
我们就找他帮拍圣诞卡片照
we should have him take our Christmas card.
做传单找出此人真实身份的主意实在太妙
Making a flyer to find out who this guy is was a great idea.
传单  你那傻儿子又走丢了吗
Flyers? Did that dopey son of yours wander off again?
才不是
No.
那是谁走丢了
Well, who's lost, then?
你家疯奶奶
Your crazy old grandmother?
那不就是你嘛  曾奶奶
That's you, Maw Maw.
阿诺德  快把这张照片扔出去
Arnold! Get this picture out of my house.
你认识这人
You know who this is?
认识  这混小子睡了我女儿
Yeah. That's the bastard who knocked my daughter up.
睡了你女儿的混蛋  那不就是
So the guy who knocked up your daughter... would be...
-我爹  -等等我想想
- My father?!  - No. Wait.
就是你爹
Your father!
如果你认识此人
请拨555-0137
我第一眼看到这个恶心男人的时候
I knew this no-good, disgusting excuse for a man was trouble
就知道肯定没好事
the minute I laid eyes on him.
但他是我爹啊
But he's my father.
爷爷就是你爹
Paw Paw was your father.
阿诺德只是个道德沦丧的混蛋
Arnold's just an immoral, horrible person.
你不会想和那种人扯上关系的
You don't want to associate with people like that.
所以你就编了个维吉尼亚她爹
So you just made up a story about Virginia's father dying
死在马赛中的故事
in a horse racing accident?
你为什么要这么做啊
Why would you do that?
因为那时你想要一匹小马和一个爸爸
Because you wanted a pony and a father,
这不是一石二鸟嘛
and it solved two problems at once.
我们还是去找你爹吧
Well... guess we'd better go meet your dad.
不去  如果他想走进我生活的话
No way. If he wanted to be a part of my life,
他多得是机会来找我
he had plenty of chances to talk to me.
我觉得你需要点菲尔医生总爱说的
But I think you're gonna need some of that...
著名心理医生与主持人
那什么感情什么东西
emotional stuff Dr. Phil's always talking about.
就是  你不能用红柄梳子修轮胎
The... "You can't fix a flat tire with a red-handled hairbrush."
不是这句
Nah, that's not it.
爹  妈
Ma! Dad!
快看看我刚为父女舞会
Check out the moves I just taught Hope
教给喜旺的舞步
for the father-daughter dance!
得了吧  吉米
Oh, come on, Jimmy.
这样下去她什么时候才能学会自己跳舞
How is she supposed to ever learn to dance on her own?
压抑小孩才能  这是哪门子的爹啊
What the hell kind of father smothers his daughter like that?
维吉尼亚  你心情不好
Virginia, you're obviously upset.
哥一般不喝啤酒  但一喝起来
"I don't always drink beer, but when I do..."
不  这也不是菲尔医生说的
Nah, that's not Dr. Phil.
拜托  顺手关门好吗  虫子都飞进来了
And for God's sake, you're letting all the bugs in. Close the door.
了断[关闭]  就是这个了
Closure-- that's it!
你得去见见你爹  做个了断
You got to go meet your dad for closure.
好吧  我去
Fine, I'll go.
但那可不是因为我信菲尔医生
But it's not because I trust Dr. Phil.
只是在《实习医生格蕾》里
It's 'cause that closure thing
这套理论似乎还挺管用
always seems to work on Grey's Anatomy.
我手都开始抖了
Oh, my hand's shaking.
自从吉米出生后  我好久都没这么紧张过了
I haven't been this nervous since Jimmy was born.
至少生吉米时我还能抽烟缓和一下
At least I had cigarettes to get me through that.
放松放松
Don't be nervous.
想象一下你爹只穿内裤的样子
Just picture your dad in his underwear.
伯特  关键是我不认识他
Burt, I've never met the man.
不知道他穿啥样的内裤啊
I don't know what sort of underwear he wears.
不好意思
No, I'm sorry, no, uh...
我今天不需要家政服务  也不用修理草坪
no housekeeping or lawn care today.
一看就知道你们是干这行的
Assuming that's what you do.
少废话  别以为我不知道你是谁
Cut the crap. I know who you are
我还知道你这么多年来干的那些鬼事
and I know what you've been doing all these years,
赶紧给我收手
and it needs to stop.
-离我家人远点  -好
- Stay away from my family... - Okay.
把偷拍我们的照片删干净
...and delete all those creepy pictures of us.
然后有多远滚多远
And then I want you to go away
别再阴魂不散了
and never come near us again.
不过你先告诉我
Right after you tell me
为什么一个人能够
what possible reason a person could have
如此狠心抛弃自己年幼的宝贝女儿
to abandon his precious baby girl.
因为我是基佬
I'm gay.
我晕
I'm confused.
我当年就是同性恋了
So was I, back then.
一切都发生在后台
You see, it all started backstage
那晚在餐厅剧院有一场《皮蓬》
after a dinner theater performance of Pippin.
我演皮蓬
I played Pippin,
当地的评论家都盛赞我的表演可谓精彩绝伦
local critic said I was "mesmerizing."
庆功宴后
After the cast party,
一瓶苹果酒把我和你妈都给放倒了
your mom, me, and a bottle of apple wine--
于是我们晕头转向地进了道具室
we, made our way into the prop closet.
维吉妮亚  这也许可以解释
Virginia, that's probably where you get
为什么你这么喜欢喝果酒
your love of fruit-based alcohol.
假装非常享受与那姑娘滚床单
Pretending to enjoy sex with a woman
是我那晚的第二场精彩演出
was perhaps my second great performance that evening.
一不小心就当上爹了
Your mom got pregnant,
而我
and I got...
我大大方方地出了柜
I got the guts to admit that I am gay.
我也不想走
I wanted to stay,
但1973年的纳什维尔
but no, the-the people of Natesville in 1973,
没有我的容身之地
they did not want to be associated with, "my kind."
这就是曾奶奶生气的原因
That's what Maw Maw was talking about.
她恨死你了
She hates you.
是啊  曾爷爷也不怎么高兴
Yeah, Paw Paw wasn't so thrilled either.
你有没有尝过穿着羊绒喇叭裤
You ever tried dodging buckshot
躲避大铅弹的滋味
in cashmere bell-bottoms?
想想都痛苦
I can only imagine.
我曾穿着牛仔短裤尝试过  已经很不易了
I did it in jean shorts and that wasn't easy.
真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
这不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
是我不好
Was my fault.
我不希望你在成长的过程中
I didn't want you to grow up
总是被人嘲笑有一个基佬爸爸
with the stigma of having a gay father.
我只能请求你的原谅
I can only hope you'll forgive me.
爹地
Daddy!
当老妈弄清楚  她爸当年为何要离开后
Once my mom understood why her dad had left,
她就没法再对他生气了
it was hard to stay mad at him.
冰淇淋
他们也都想追回
And they both wanted to make up for lost time
曾经错过的父女时光
doing all those father-daughter things they missed out on.
你的奶子就和布里的车轮一样大[法语]
Vos mamelons sont comme des roues de Brie.
他说...
He said...
他说了啥
What'd he say?
我还指望今晚能吃上墨西哥肉卷呢
I was really looking forward to taco night.
别这样  伯特
Oh, come on, Burt.
你的味蕾也太单调了
Your palate is so pedestrian.
何不尝试点新鲜事物呢
Why don't you try something new?
寿司不就是远东的墨西哥卷
Sushi is the taco of the Far East.
你看啊
Now, look.
这里面富含蛋白质
You've got your protein,
和碳水化合物
you've got your rice,
都用不着玉米饼
and instead of a corn tortilla,
光一片海苔
it's all wrapped
便将美味与营养尽裹
in a delicious piece of mori.
如果忽略它的制作食材的话  那就好吃多了
If you ignore-i what it's made of, it tastes p pretty good.
海胆怎么样  伯特
How is that sea urchin, Burt?
就好像大海在我嘴里打了个喷嚏
It's like the ocean sneezed in my mouth.
这么多年来  我背着相机跟踪你们时
You know, all those years I've been following you guys around with a camera,
多么渴望自己能走上来
and I feel like I've just walked
成为那画面中的一份子
right into the picture.
我们应该拍张全家福
You know, we should have a family photo.
-我最爱拍全家福了  -必须有主题
- I love family photos. - With a theme.
带主题的全家福什么的最喜欢了
I love family photos with themes!
纳什维尔古董博物馆
太棒了
This is amazing.
我最爱角色扮演了
I love costumes.
亲爱的  我是否有幸
Oh, boy, do I have a parade
将你永远留在这一刻
to take you to next summer.
这肯定会是有史以来最漂亮的全家福
This is gonna be the best family photo ever.
维吉妮亚  我得和你谈谈
Virginia, I gotta talk to you.
超适合我的是不是
Isn't this the cat's pajamas?
是啊
Yes.
你就把自己的快乐建立在别人的丑态上
But only because I think cat's pajamas are stupid.
你爸爸给我挑的这身
I look like an idiot
穿起来就像个白痴
in this thing your dad picked out.
别这样  伯特
Oh, come on, Burt.
多好玩啊
This is fun.
不  不好玩
No, it's not fun.
阿诺德一来就没什么好事
Nothing's been fun since Arnold showed up.
你是在吃醋吗
Are you jealous
就因为我总是和爸爸在一起
because I'm spending time with my dad?
不是  但我知道
No. But I just know that
他看不惯我的行为作风
he doesn't like the way I act
话不投机  饭也吃不到一块儿
or what I say or what I like to eat.
他对我简直百般挑剔
He doesn't like anything about me.
那你希望我怎么做
So what do you want me to do?
他是我爸爸啊
He's my father.
我以后都不能见他了吗
Am I supposed to not see him anymore?
我不是这个意思
I didn't say that.
我只是希望他能离开  再也不要出现
I just would like him to go away and never come back.
他让我觉得很不舒服  维吉妮亚
He makes me uncomfortable, Virginia.
他跟我们不是一类人
He's just too different than us.
听到这里的人
Wish I could say I was surprised
说出这样的话
to hear that kind of intolerance
还真是意料之中
from someone in this town.
他就在我身后  是不是
He's right behind me, isn't he?
伯特  这话要在人家还没开口之前就问
Burt, that only works if he hasn't said anything.
很抱歉我跟你不是一类人  伯特
Sorry to be so different from you, Burt.
显然你老公不赞同我的生活方式
Obviously your husband doesn't approve of my lifestyle.
不  不  那不是我的真实想法
No, no. Honestly, I didn't mean that.
只是你喜欢的一切
It's just that everything you like to do
让我觉得难受不适
makes me uncomfortable or sick.
看来想要融入你的生活是大错特错了
Trying to be a part of your life was clearly a mistake.
我不适合演情景喜剧
I'm not one for melodrama, so...
永别了
good-bye forever.
伯特
Burt...
我们刚刚父女重聚
I just got my dad back,
你就把他赶走了
and now you drove him away.
我能处理好的
I can fix this.
还记得那次我打碎了你最爱的茶杯吗
Like when I broke your favorite mug.
就是那个每次喝水  我都会头晕目眩的茶杯吗
The mug that makes me dizzy every time I drink from it?
没错
Good point.
我保证  这次绝不用劣质有毒胶水
I promise I will not use the same toxic glue
来修复我和你爸爸的关系
to fix your dad.
老爸因为阿诺德外公的事很内疚
Dad felt so bad about what happened with Grandpa Arnold
所以他不仅在全家福中出镜凹造型
that he not only posed for the family picture,
还决定为此举办一个聚会
he decided to throw a party
让纳什维尔的其他人都来欢迎阿诺德回家
so the rest of Natesville could welcome Arnold home.
他是个快乐的基佬
For he's a jolly gay fellow
他是个开心的基佬
For he's a jolly gay fellow...
我原谅你们  纳什维尔人民
I forgive you, Natesville.
这点毋庸置疑
Which nobody can deny.
后来我舍弃了终身职位
And then I left a... a tenured position
转而去做一名自由人种音乐学家
to become a freelance ethnomusicologist.
我曾在非洲的村落里见过一个男人
I once saw a man in a small African village
单凭一个石头和人的牙齿
who could perform an entire symphony
就演奏出一首完整的交响曲
using nothing but a rock and a human tooth.
天呐  真是美妙极了
Ah... Oh! Was it amazing?
不是  听得我想死
Oh, no, it was... it was excruciating.
但他的努力确实值得敬佩  是吧
But you had to admire the effort, right?
他周游列国  连加拿大都去过
He's been all over the world. Even Canada.
学一下加拿大口音  老爸
Do your Canadian accent, Dad.
维吉妮亚是我闺女
Virginia's my daughter, eh?
跟在看现场版冰球赛似的[加拿大人擅打冰球]
It's like we're at a hockey game.
这是在给我过生日  还是守灵呢
This my birthday or my wake?
把她弄进去
Go get her back inside.
我不想让她看到我爸  然后不停地攻击同性恋
I don't want her to see my father and start gay-bashing.
好
Okay.
给你守灵呢  你来早了
It's your wake and you're early.
咱们进屋吧
Let's get you back inside.
那个不要脸的混蛋怎么在这
What the hell is that depraved son of a bitch doing here?
他是我爸爸
He's my father,
是我邀请他来的
and I invited him here.
这还是我家
This is still my house,
我不想这种恶心
and I don't want that kind of disgusting,
下流  变态
immoral, deviant...
曾奶奶  你不能再说这种话了
Maw Maw, you can't say stuff like that anymore.
好吗  都2013年了
Okay? It's 2013.
我靠  老娘也活得忒久了
Damn it, this life is taking forever.
听着
Look...
我们都接受了真正的他
we all accept my dad for who he is.
纳什维尔的人已经不介意他是同性恋了
Nobody in Natesville cares anymore that he's gay.
他是同性恋
He's gay?
我对同性恋没意见
Well, I don't have a problem with gays.
吉米就是同性恋  但我依然爱他
I mean, Jimmy's gay, and I love him
还有他的小老公
and his little husband.
这是她对我说过的最动听的话了
Oh, that's the nicest thing she's ever said to me.
但那家伙
But that guy?
他是世界第一自恋狂
He's a first-class narcissist.
自恋狂
Oh, "Narcissist."
咱们应该都知道这词的意思吧
I think we know what that's code for.
你哪个词没听懂
You fall asleep in the middle of sentences?
他是个自私的混蛋
He's a selfish jerk.
他只关心自己
He doesn't care about anybody but himself.
这就是他离开你和你妈的原因
That's why he left you and your mother.
他没离开
He didn't leave.
他只是出城了  对吧
He was run out of town. Right?
对  出城
Well, "Run out of town,"
就是感觉不受欢迎
"Made to feel unwelcome,
不被赏识  都一样
unappreciated..." Same diff.
我觉得不一样
I don't think it really is the same.
说着容易
That's easy for you to say.
你试试70年代生活在这个小镇
You try being gay and raising a child
当个同性恋还要养个孩子
in this town in the '70s.
说到这个
You know, now that you mention it...
我那一对女同妈妈就是70年代在这把我养大的
my lesbian mothers raised me in this town in the '70s.
虽然  她俩中的一个得打扮成男人
Sure, one of them had to dress up like a man
才带我去参加父子独木舟旅行
to take me on the father-son canoe trip,
但她们都挺过来了
but they toughed it out.
不过这都没什么  因为她本来就有小胡子
It didn't hurt that she already had a mustache
和一柜子的男士衣装
and a closet full of flannels.
女同
Lesbians.
女同人人爱
Everybody loves lesbians.
你至少可以给她写封信嘛
You could've at least written her a letter.
但你连个电话都没打过
Or not even a phone call?
70年代有电话的
They had phones in the '70s.
-没错吧  -没错
- Right? - Yep. Right.
电话公司跟同性恋...
The phone company and-and gay people...
你分明就是拿同性恋做借口
You're clearly using your homosexuality as an excuse
来掩盖你拒绝承担为人父责任的事实
to cover up for your refusal to accept your parental responsibilities.
对了  还没正式介绍
By the way, we haven't met.
我是弗兰克
I'm Frank.
幸会
It's a pleasure.
再说一遍  纳什维尔恨我的人
Once again, the haters of Natesville
都高昂着他们丑恶的头颅
rear their ugly heads.
你们这群人真有意思
You know, you people are very interesting,
就是不肯悔改
because you don't seem to be able to change, do you?
你才是死不悔改的人吧
Maybe you're the one who hasn't changed.
因为我想了一下
'Cause now that I'm thinking about it,
我们这周做的所有事
everything that we've done this week
都是按照你的意愿
has been something you wanted to do.
我们按你的意愿吃了寿司
We had that sushi dinner 'cause you wanted it.
你提议星期二吃玉米卷
You suggested Taco Tuesday.
你不会真想让我
Do you honestly expect me
吃移民摆的路边摊吧
to eat the street food of a migrant people?
我们看了你挑的法国电影
We went to that French movie 'cause you picked it.
瑞典版的爹已经看过了
Already saw the Swedish version.
你还坚持
And you insisted
让我们拍那个主题的全家福
on the theme for our family picture.
因为我想把照片给我的朋友们看
Because I wanted to share it with my friends.
你还不明白吗
Don't you understand?
你们穿成平常那样拍照
Do you honestly expect me to show a photo of-of you guys
你真觉得这种照片拿得出手吗
dressed the way you normally do?
对不起  我错了
Forgive me for trying
我不该让你们显得更有格调
to raise you to a higher level.
你可以再一次
I think you should leave...
离开了
again.
但这次  是我让你离开的
But this time, it's my choice.
永别了
Good-bye forever.
这个我要带走  因为我照得还挺帅的
I'm gonna take this because I look fantastic.
有时候爸爸不在你身旁
Sometimes your dad's not here
有时候你爸是个自私的大...
Sometimes your dad's a big selfish...
歇了吧  雪莉
Quit it, Shelley.
那晚我爸邀请所有人来见我妈的爸爸
Dad invited everyone over that night to meet Mom's father.
但原来他们早就认识我妈的爸爸了
But in the end, it turned out they already knew her father,
因为曾爷爷才是我妈的真爸爸
because Paw Paw was Mom's real dad.
真遗憾
I'm sorry your gay father
你的基爹原来是个自恋狂魔
turned out to be a narcissist.
你还好吧
You okay?
挺好
Yeah.
其实以前我以为爸爸是个好人
The truth is, I had a pretty good father figure.
所以阿诺德在我小时候就离开也是件好事
And I guess it's good Arnold left when I was a baby.
给我省了多少高档通心粉啊
Think of all the macaroni art I would have wasted on that guy.
还有手指画
Finger-paintings.
-烟灰缸  -难看的领带
- Ashtrays. - Ugly ties.
他可能会给
He probably would've given me zero stars
我为他做的父亲节早餐打零分
on the Father's Day breakfast I made him.
而且
And besides...
如果我正经有个爹
if I didn't have some daddy issues,
我可能不会15岁就被搞大了肚子
I might not have got knocked up at 15.
那样如今的我会是什么样呢
Then where would I be?